丑裸男在装饰他的树
Ugly Naked Guy is decorating his tree.
天啊  你们真该瞧瞧他圣诞球的大小
Oh my God, you should see the size of his Christmas Balls.
你们今年给管理员多少红包
How much did you tip the super this year?
是这样  我们打算给50
Yeah, we were gonna give fifty,
不过我们不想显得比你们小气
but if you guys gave more, we don't wanna look bad.
今年我们准备送他自己做的饼干
Oh, actually this year we just made him homemade cookies.
那就包25块好了
And 25 it is.
你们送他饼干
You gave them cookies?
给钱太见外了
Money is so impersonal.
饼干能表达我们对他的关心
Cookies says someone really cares.
好吧  我们没钱  但饼干真能表达那层意思
Alright, we're broke, but cookies do say that.
我了解
I can see that.
曾有盘布朗尼对我念过打油诗
A plate of brownies told me a limerick.
菲比  问你个事  那些是"搞怪"布朗尼吗
Pheebs, let me ask you something. Were these "funny" brownies?
不算吧
Not especially.
不过我觉得里面放了大麻
But I think they had pot in them.
两位  你们还送了谁饼干
So you guys, who else did you tip with cookies?
邮差  管理员
The mailman, the super....
还有那个送报纸的
And the newspaper delivery guy.
天呐
Oh, my God.
怎么了
What?
你们可能看到会不开心
I don't think you're not gonna like this.
天呐  这些饼干在运动版被碾碎了
Ooh, goooosh, ooh, these are cookies smashed in the sports section.
看  他还把我的字谜给做了
Look. He did my crossword puzzle.
对  但是错误百出
Yeah, but not very well,
除非横十四的"格什温音乐剧"
unless 14 across, "Gershwin musical"...
是叫"咬我  咬我  咬我"
...actually is "Bite me, bite me, bite me."
真不敢相信这就到圣诞节了
I can't believe it's Christmas already.
我们才刚吃完了感恩火鸡  一转眼
One day you're eating turkey, the next thing you know...
就该唱"跳跃的男人"和"生蛋的鹅"了
your lords are a-leapin' and you geese are a-layin'.
所以每年这个时候  鹅才会感到如释重负
Which is why geese are so relaxed this time of year.
各位
Hey, guys.
瑞秋
Hey, Rach.
我买了一个小礼物给你
I got you a little present.
我来拆
I'll open it.
是个小司令
It's a Slinky!
记得吗
Remember?
你走下楼梯  单独或成双
Walks downstairs Alone or in pairs
大家都知道是...
Everyone knows it's
只是一个大弹簧
Just a big spring.
好吧  你还在生我的气  因为...
You're still mad at me because of the whole...
那份对我描述不符的讨厌列表吗
Horrible degrating list of reasons not to be with me?
从现在起我们称那为"小插曲"怎么样
How 'bout from now on we just call it the 'unfortunate incident'?
甘瑟  你家里有没有楼梯
Hey, Gunther. You got stairs in your place?
-有  -拿去玩吧
- Yeah. - Go nuts.
各位
Hey, guys.
袋子里是什么
What's in the bag?
一些礼物而已
Just some presents.
快拿出来瞧瞧
Come on, show us what you bought.
少装了
You know you want to.
好的
OK.
好吧  你们看  这是本送给我父母的相框
This is a picture frame from Ben to my parents.
很可爱
Oh, that's cute.
我买了拉拉情侣毛巾给苏珊跟卡罗尔
I got some, uh, hers and hers towels for Susan and Carol.
我还买了这件衬衫给妈
And I got this blouse for Mom.
罗斯  好漂亮
Ross, that is gorgeous!
瞧瞧这些假徽章
Look at these authentic fake metals!
妈会在虚构的军校里
I tell ya, mom's gonna be voted "best dressed"...
获选"最佳着装奖"
...at the make-believe military academy!
菲比
Hi, Phoebe.
-平安夜前夜快乐  -同乐
-Happy "Christmas Eve" Eve. - You too.
我的天  这是这哪儿来的
Oh, my God! Where did you get this?
梅西百货三楼  家饰部
Macy's, third floor, home furnishings.
这是我爸爸
This is my father!
这是我爸爸的照片
This is a picture of my dad!
菲比  那是相框附送的相片
Nah, Phoebs, that's the guy that comes in the frame.
不  这是我爸爸  好  我拿给你们看
No it isn't, this is my dad, alright, I'll show you.
菲比  你爸不是还在监狱吗
Phoebe, I thought your dad was in prison.
不  那是我继父
No, that's my stepdad.
我的生父是我出生以前就跑了的那个
My real dad's the one that ran out on us before I was born.
你这口才没上奥普拉脱口秀真是屈才了
How have you never been on Oprah?
瞧  这就是他
Look, see? This is him.
我妈在死前给了我这张照片  是同一个人
My mother gave me this picture before she died. Same guy!
亲爱的  相片上一个相框模特
Honey, uh, this is a picture of the frame guy
在浅蓝背景前摆造型  旁边有只牧羊犬
...posing in front of a blue screen with a collie.
那不是蓝背景  那是...
It's not a blue screen. It's just....
也许那天万里晴空吧
Maybe it was just really clear that day.
我得跟我外婆谈一谈
Okay, I have to talk to my grandmother.
-等一下  亲爱的  -菲比
- Wait a minute, honey! - Phoebs.
我在设法骗我老板的前任老婆上床
So anyway I'm trying to get my boss's ex-wife to sleep with me.
乔伊
Joey!
菲比有问题时  大家都洗耳恭听
But when Phoebe has a problem, everyone's all ears!
埃丝特·利文斯顿
Esther Livingston.
死了
Gone!
丫头
Hi, Pooh.
外婆  你在干什么
Hi, Gram. What you doing?
更新电话簿
Just updating the phone book.
外婆
Gram?
我可以再看一次我爸的照片吗
Can I see the pictures of my dad again?
当然可以了
Sure, sure.
怎么了
How come?
我只是突然想看一看
Just, you know, to see him.
好  来
Sure. Here.
这是你爸站在草地上的照片
This is the one of your father in a meadow.
他帮一个小男孩放风筝
And helping a little boy fly a kite.
这一张是他参加毕业典礼
And here he is at a graduation.
另一张毕业照
Another graduation.
还是毕业照
他真的是我爸吗
Is this really my father?
他真的是你爸
Is it really your fa?
天呐  当然是了
Oh, god. Well, of course it is.
气氛不对啊  我看有人在说谎
I smell smoke. Maybe because someone's pants are on fire!
我从出生到现在
In all the years we've been grandmother and granddaughter...
你从没对我撒过谎
...you've never lied to me.
好吧  他不是你爸爸  他只是一个相框模特
All right, that's not your father. It's a picture of a guy in a frame.
天啊
Oh, God.
那是你妈的主意
It was your mother's idea.
她不想让你知道谁是你爸
She didn't want you to know your real father...
因为他的离开把你妈的心给伤透了
... because he hurt her so much when he left.
我也不想跟着骗你
I didn't want to go wrong with her.
可是她死了  那样跟她争就更难了
But then she died and it was harder to argue with her.
不是不可能  只是更难
Not impossible, but harder.
那他就不是一个有名的树医
All right. So he's not a famous tree surgeon?
他也不住在没有电话的缅甸茅屋里头
And I guess he doesn't live in a hut in Burma where there's no phones?
我听说他在纽约州某个地方当药剂师
Last I heard, he was a pharmacist somewhere upstate.
那没有道理
That makes no sense.
村民们为什么要崇拜一个药剂师呢
Why would the villagers worship a pharmacist?
亲爱的
Honey.
反正我所知道的就这么多
Anyway, that's all I know.
还有
That...
这个
...and this.
这
This...
是他本人
...is the real him.
我记得我爸爸  他穿了一身火红的衣服
I remember my father all dressed up in the red suit...
黑色的大靴子  还有漆皮皮带
...the big black boots and the patent leather belt...
在楼下鬼鬼崇崇的  他不想被任何人发现
...sneaking around downstairs. He didn't want us to see him...
可是他醉得东倒西歪
but he'd be drunk so he'd stumble,
然后撞东撞西  把大家都吵醒
crash into something and wake everybody up.
听起来不像是个快乐的圣诞节
That doesn't sound like a very merry Christmas.
谁说起圣诞节了
Who said anything about Christmas?
有没有菲比的消息
Anyone hear from Phoebe yet?
没有
No, nothing.
希望她没事
I hope she's okay.
是啊  我清楚知道她的处境
Yeah. I know exactly what she's going through.
你怎么会清楚知道她的处境
How do you know exactly what she's going through?
她告诉我们的
She told us.
摩妮卡  你买了什么
What do you got there, Monica?
派对要用的东西
Just some stuff for the party.
你们还在这里干什么  你们不是该去买礼物了吗
What are you guys doing here?Aren't you guys supposed to be shopping?
你们礼物还没买好吗
You didn't buy presents yet?
明天就是平安夜了  你们要怎么办
Tomorrow's Christmas Eve! What are you gonna do?
不是黏土动画里面的人才会那么说的吗
Don't you have to be Claymation to say stuff like that?
对了  摩妮卡  我想邮差不喜欢你的饼干
Oh, by the way Mon, I don't think the mailman liked your cookies.
这是你妈寄来的装饰品
Here are the ornaments your mom sent.
说不定他喜欢我的饼干  只是嫌少了
Maybe the mailman liked the cookies. We just didn't give him enough.
摩妮卡  鸽子的觉悟都比你高
Monica, pigeons learn faster than you.
瑞秋
Hey, Rach.
我想我知道怎么样让你好过点了
I think I know what will make you feel better.
你也写张关于我的列表怎么样
How about you make a list about me?
什么  算了吧  罗斯  我才不会列...
Forget it. Ross. I'm not gonna stand here....and make a list
好  你爱发牢骚
Okay, you're whiny...
没完没了  疑神疑鬼
...you are obsessive, you are insecure...
没有胆量
...you're gutless.
你从来不知道怎么"把握时机"
You don't ever just "seize the day."
你暗恋我一年了吧  结果你一直憋在心里
You liked me for a year and you didn't do anything about it.
还有  你头发涂了太多发胶了
And you wear too much of that gel in your hair.
瞧
See, there....
你听我的了
All right, you did what I said.
对  你知道吗  你说得对  我的确好多了
Yeah, you know what? You're right. I do feel better.
谢了  罗斯
Thank you, Ross.
对  在奥尔巴尼  我想查弗兰克·布菲的电话
Yeah, in Albany. Could I have the number of Frank Buffay?
好  那伊萨卡的呢
Okay. In Ithaca?
好吧  沙拉托加呢
All right, Saratoga?
奥尼昂塔呢
Oneonta?
好吧  你知道吗  你没有资格自称查号台
You know what? You shouldn't call yourself Information!
外婆  如果这是你真名的话
Hello, Grandma. If that is, in fact, your real name.
好了  丫头  别跟我生气了
Come on now, Pooh. Don't still be mad at me.
-查得怎么样了  -不太好
- How's it going? - Not so good.
纽约州那么大  他那么渺小  你自己算算
Upstate's pretty big. He's pretty small. You do the math.
我觉得你还是别找了
Well, I think you're better off without him.
我知道他是你爸
Oh, honey, I know he's your daddy.
但是对我而言  他是个不负责任的混球
But to me, he's still the irresponsible creep...
让你妈怀孕  又偷她的车子
...who locked up your mom and stole her Gremlin.
我知道  只是想知道他是谁而已
I know. I just wanted to know who he was, you know?
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I know.
我说我不知道他的住处
I wasn't completely honest with you when I told you that,
其实是骗你的
uh, I didn't know exactly where he lived.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他住在米德尔顿罗瑞尔路74号
He lives at 74 Laurel Drive in Middletown.
看到"冰雪皇后"就说明过头了
If you hit the Dairy Queen, you've gone too far.
开我的车去吧
You can take my cab.
谢了
Thank you.
-我的出租车可别让其他人开  -知道了
- Now, remember, nobody else drives that cab. - Got it.
我要见到我爸了
I'm gonna see my dad!
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧  祝我好运了  爷爷
O.K. Wish me luck, Grandpa.
菲比的出租车到了吗
Phoebe here with the cab yet?
到了  那是一辆隐形车
Yeah, she brought the invisible cab.
上车吧
Hop in!
她最好快一点  工厂直销店七点就关门了
Well she better get here soon, the outlet stores close at 7.
别急  我想菲比去她爸那儿大概两个小时
Hey, don't worry. I figure it'll be 2 hours to Phoebe's dad's house,
他们见面  聊天  交流生活中发生的事
they'll meet, they'll chat, they'll swap life stories,
还有很多时间的
we'll have plenty of time.
她来了
Hey, here she comes!
你们相信吗
Can you believe this?
再过两个小时我就有爸了
In, like, two hours I'm gonna have a dad.
是啊  大事哦
Yeah, big stuff!
好  走吧
Okay, let's go!
-给  你拿着这张纸  -好
- Here, you have to hold this. - OK.
"左脚刹车  右脚油门"
"Brake, left. Gas, right"?
对  我的小抄
That's my cheat sheet.
-安全带呢   -你那边没有了
- Where's my seat belt? - Oh, no no, that side doesn't have one,
被救护人员剪开了
The paramedics had to cut through it.
告诉我吧  拜托
Come on, just tell me. Please, please!
我说第十六遍  不  我觉得你不是没完没了
For the 16th time: No, I do not think you're obsessive!
-这里都成蒸笼了  -瑞秋  把暖气关小
- Oh, gosh, it's hot in here! - Rach, get the heat.
罗斯  把暖气关小
Ross, turn the heat down, please?
好  对了  这两个词之间是有差别  一个是...
Sure. By the way, there's a difference between being obsessive and...
罗斯  调暖气
Ross, the heat!
好  暖气  暖气  暖气  还说我没完没了
Okay! Heat, heat, heat! And I'm the obsessive one?
好吧  往这边拧是开
Okay. This way is on.
往这边拧是...
So this is...
关
...off.
你把暖气片弄坏了
Did you just break the radiator?
没有  我刚在转把手
No, I was turning the knob and...
结果就掉了
... here it is.
那就装回去
Well, put it back!
装不回去了
It won't go back.
我打电话给管理员
I'll call the super.
来  我来试试
Here, let me try.
对了  我忘了你融合金属的能力了
That's right. I forgot about your ability to fuse metal.
你在说"笑话"的表亲
Hey, it's Funny's cousin...
"不好笑"
... Not Funny!
崔戈先生
Hi, Mr. Treeger?
我是楼上的瑞秋·格林
It's Rachel Greene from upstairs.
对  有人弄坏了我们暖气片的把手
Yes, somebody broke our knob on the radiator...
我们这里好热
...and it's really hot in here.
对  热到可以烤饼干了
Yes, it's hot enough to bake cookies.
你能在六点前帮我们换上新的吗
Well, do you think we could have a new one by 6?
什么  不  不  周二  我们等不到周二
What, no, no, Tuesday, we can't wait until Tuesday,
我们今晚有派对
We're having a party tonight.
好吧  给他小费
Okay, tip the man.
不  不喜欢我们的饼干就算了吧
No, if he doesn't like our cookies, too bad,
我才不要任人勒索呢
I won't be blackmailed.
最坏的打算  如果这里有点热
Look if worse comes to worse, it gets a little warm,
就改成主题派对好了
we'll call it a theme party.
这下有主题了  "快请进  体验被烤熟的滋味吧"
Here's a theme: "Come on in, live like bacon!"
就是这里
This is it!
74号
Seventy-four.
长途跋涉  终于到了
So that's what this is for!
就是这里  我要见到我爸了
This is it. I'm gonna meet my dad.
这真是我的人生头等大事
This is like the biggest thing ever.
没错
Sure is.
好了  我要进去了
Here I go. I'm going in.
好啊
All right!
一切顺利  菲比
Good luck, Pheebs.
好了  我走了
Here I go.
我走了
我要走了
I'm going.
欢迎光临我们的热带圣诞派对
Welcome to our tropical Christmas party.
外套  毛衣  长裤跟衬衫  请放在卧室里面
Put your coats, sweaters, pants and shirts in the bedroom.
我在冒汗  所以看不出来
It's hard to tell because I'm sweating...
但我完全遵照瓶上指示的用量
... but I use exactly what the gel bottle says.
一颗豆子大小的份量而已
An amount about the size of a pea.
那怎么会过量呢
How can that be too much?
要冰块吗
Ice?
冰块来了  谁要冰块  拿张餐巾  好的
Ice? Ice squares anyone? Take a napkin. All right.
摩妮卡  摩妮卡  摩妮卡
Monica! Monica! Monica!
你的客人都快被烤成人干了
Your guests are turning into jerky. OK?
真的吗  我觉得舒服得很
Really? I'm perfectly comfortable.
排队  兄弟  换我了
Hey! Get in line, buddy. I was next.
崔戈先生
Mr. Treeger.
你说有派对
You said there was a party.
欢迎来蒸桑拿
Well, hey, welcome to our sauna.
很热吗  我从来不觉得热
Is it hot? My body always stays cool.
说不定是因为我表皮太多了
Probably because I have so much skin.
奶酪
Hey, cheese!
好吧  好吧  机会来了  摩妮卡  给他现金
Here's the chance. Monica, give him cash.
瑞秋  把你的耳环给他  快  有什么给什么
Rachel, give him your earrings. Something. Anything!
不  我不屈服
No, I will not cave.
对  我也是
Yeah. I'm with Mon.
好吧  你说我从不把握机会
All right. You know how you say I never seize the day?
他虽然是你们的管理员  我也要把握一下
Even though he's your super, I'm seizing.
崔戈先生
Mr. Treeger?
这里是50块钱  圣诞节快乐
Here is $50. Merry Christmas.
我没有准备你的礼物
I didn't get you anything.
返你5块钱好了
Here's five back.
不  那是你的圣诞红包
No, that's your Christmas tip.
你现在可以把暖气片给修好吗
Do you think there's a chance you can fix that radiator now?
没办法  我已经告诉姑娘们了
No can do. Like I told the girl...
星期二才拿得到新的把手
... I can't get a knob until Tuesday.
罗斯
Ross?
看来他很"僵硬"哦
Looks like he's playin' baseball.
你要说"强硬"吧
You mean hardball?
管它呢
Whatever.
你打算怎么样呢
What you gonna do?
先失陪  我要把握时机
Excuse me. I'm seizing.
崔戈先生
Mr. Treeger?
我再给你五十
Here's another 50.
光明节快乐
Happy Hanukkah.
这样我们就可以拿到新的把手了吧
Will this help with the knob-getting?
不行  那家店星期二才会开门
No, the place is not open till Tuesday.
我的发音不标准吗
Am I not saying it right?
你真的喜欢我的饼干吗
So you really did like my cookies?
是啊  很用心  足够表达你们对我的关心了
Yeah, they were so personal. It really showed you cared.
把握得好
Nice seizing...
发胶兄
...gel boy.
这是檞寄生吧
Is this mistletoe?
不  那叫...
No, that....
叫甜罗勒
That is basil.
如果是檞寄生  我就要亲你了
If it was mistletoe, I was gonna kiss you.
不  那还是甜罗勒
No, it's still basil.
*火炉上烤栗子*
*Chestnuts roasting on an open fire*
*雪人在啃你的鼻子*
*Jack Frost nipping at your nose*
-你走到哪里了  -信箱
- How far did you get? - Mailbox.
有进步了
All right, we're getting closer.
菲比  你怎么了
Phoebs, what's goin' on?
其实原因很多
It's just like a whole mess of stuff.
昨天  我爸还是一个名闻遐迩的缅甸树医
Like yesterday, my dad was this famous Burma tree-surgeon guy.
可他转眼成了药剂师
And you know, now he's a pharmacist guy and....
也可能他是一个很不错的药剂师
Well, maybe he's this really cool pharmacist guy.
对  有可能  对  然后我会跑去敲他家的门
Yeah, maybe! And I'll knock on the door...
他会拥抱我  我会有个爸爸
...and he'll hug me, and I'll have a dad!
然后大家都会对我很友善
I'll go to his pharmacy and everyone will be nice to me...
因为我是弗兰克的女儿
... because, you know, I'm Frank's daughter.
那怎么不去敲门
So why not go knock?
因为如果他不够做父亲的资格呢
Because, I mean, what if he's not this great-dad guy?
如果他还是那个抛妻弃女的浑球呢
What if he's still the dirtbag who ran out on my mom and us?
你知道吗
You know what?
我这个礼拜已经失去一个假爸爸了
I've already lost a fake dad this week.
我不想再失去一个真的爸爸
I don't think I'm ready to lose a real one.
菲菲  没关系的  你已经跨出一大步了
Pheebs, that's okay. You took a big step today.
哪天你准备好了  就会主动去认他了
Someday, when you're ready, you'll make it past the hedges.
到那个时候  他认你这个女儿  会感到很幸运
And when you do, he'll be lucky to have you.
你们真好
You guys....
抱歉害你们来不及购物了
I'm sorry about your shopping.
没关系  会有办法的
Oh, that's okay. We'll figure something out.
我知道你不要进去
Uh, listen Phoebs, I know you're not goin' in there
但我可不可以进去借用洗手间
but do you think it'd be alright if I went in and used his bathroom?
没关系  算了
That's fine, never mind.
不错  下雪了
Cool, snow!
像空白的画布
Kind of like a blank canvas.
我的老天  这里好热
Ho-ho-ho-holy crap, is it hot in here!
介意我把暖气关小吗
Really, hey, you mind if I turn the heat down?
我们怎么都没想到呢
We could have used that kind of thinking earlier!
菲比  结果怎么样
So, Pheebs, how did it go?
我没能进去
Oh, I couldn't go in.
-亲爱的  好可惜  -你还好吗
- Honey, I'm sorry. - Are you okay?
好  没关系  因为我知道他在
Yeah, it's okay, because I know he's there.
现在这样就够了
So that's enough for now.
各位  过十二点了  祝大家圣诞快乐
Hey, guys, it's after midnight! Merry Christmas, everyone!
圣诞快乐
Oh, right! Merry Christmas!
莫妮卡  把手坏了
Hey, Monica, the knob was broken
所以我从下面关掉了  没问题吧
so I just turned it off from underneath, I hope that's alright.
瑞秋  送你的
Rach, these are for you.
汽车雨刷
Wiper blades!
我连车都没有
I don't even have a car.
对  但加上这个芳香剂  你会以为你有
No, but with this new-car smell, you'll think you do!
菲比  到你了
Okay, Pheebs, your turn.
马桶座套
Toilet-seat covers!
你们是趁我加油的时候买的吗
Is that what you were doing while I was getting gas?
你们真好
You guys!
至于罗斯
And for Ross...
甜食先生
... Mr. Sweet Tooth.
你们送我一瓶可乐
You got me a cola drink?
还有柠檬酸橙汁
And a lemon-lime!
礼物太厚礼了  我该再送你们一件毛衣
Well, this is too much! I feel like I should get you another sweater.
压轴出场了
And last, but not least....
螺纹的让你更有快感
They're ribbed for your pleasure!